《斯巴达克斯：血与沙》
《红蟒》
闭上你们的臭嘴
Hold your fucking tongues.
让罗马人说吧
Let the Roman have it say.
特雷斯和罗马之间有众所周知的矛盾
Thrace and the republic have their known differences
我们并非情同手足
We are not always being as brothers.
但是现在  我们应该不计前嫌
But let us put aside such matters
团结一致
uniting in just cause.
你们侵犯了我们的领地
You pushed away into our land
现在居然指望我们
and now you standing here asking for our help?
伸手求助
Your hand extended?
我没有伸手求助
I extend no hand.
我只不过是来传达消息
I'm here merely to inform.
米特拉达梯人和希腊人从东面进攻
Mithridatic and his Greek attack from the east
侵占了黑海
encroaching from the Black Sea.
离我们村落远着呢  没错
Far remote from our villages. True.
但是日耳曼人会趁虚而入
But the Dacians take advantage of the distraction.
他们的野蛮人大军簇居在北部
Their barbarian hordes are massed to the north.
再有三四天就会到达你们村落
barely half a week march from your villages.
有多少人  数以千计
How many?  Thousands.
投靠罗马吧
Ally yourselves with Rome.
加入我们的浩浩大军
Place your sevice in the auxiliary.
与我们共驰沙场
And join us in our campaign.
为了什么  为了什么
To what end? To what end?
胜利
Victory.
如何才算胜利
And how it is to be measured?
日耳曼人以前就侵占过我们的村落
The Dacians have invaded our villages in the past.
强暴妇女  虐杀孩童
They raped our women   killed our children.
一波未平
Each time we push them back.
一波又起
Only to see them return.
他虽然无礼的插嘴了  但说的都是事实
He speaks out of turn   yet the truth falls from his mouth.
想让我们投靠罗马  要明确目的才行
If we are to ally with Rome   the purpose must be clear.
杀死日耳曼人
The Dacians dead.
片甲不留
All of them.
杀死日耳曼人
Dead.
片甲不留
All of them.
议会决定了吗
The council has decided?
我们要参战
We go to war.
我祈求神明  为你的剑护法
I've asked the gods to bless your sword.
如果日耳曼人就此被铲除了
If the Dacians wiped out of our land
我也不再需要弄枪舞剑了
there is no reason to pick it up again.
不弄枪舞剑  我的丈夫又能做什么呢
What my husband would do without it in his hand?
锄地种田  养鸡喂鹅
Grow crops   raise goats
生儿育女
Make children.
你之后不再去打仗了吗  再也不会了
You'd fight no more?  Forever.
只为伴你左右
To be by your side.
何时行军  明日凌晨
How soon is your march?  First light.
那快上床吧
Then come to bed.
如果只剩一夜春宵
If one night is all we have left
我们应该享尽欢愉
I should make the most out of it.
我醒过来的时候希望身边能有你
I woke up expecting my wife beside me.
我早起祷告
She rose up early to pray.
祈祷我的丈夫可以留在我身边
that her husband would stay with her.
我还以为我们已经说好了
I thought we were in an agreement.
那是昨晚  昨晚?
We were.  Were?
昨晚  神明到来
The gods came to me last night.
托梦给我
in my sleep.
什么梦  我的丈夫跪在地上
What they showed you?  My husband's on his knees.
对一条红蛇俯首称臣
Bowing before a great red serpent.
生命在他的血脉中干涸
The life draining from his veins.
你觉得那代表什么
What meaning did you take from it?
一个警示
A warning.
如果你参战了  巨大的不幸将会降临
If you go to war   you are destined to great unfortunate things.
日耳曼人敬拜的是山岭狼
The Dacians worship the mountain wolves.
他们敬拜的不是蛇
They place no faith in snakes.
不过是梦一场
It was just a dream.
如果不是呢  我向你保证  苏拉
And if it isn't?  I gave you my word   Sura.
鲜血和荣耀
Blood and honor
铸就了男人
it speaks to the man.
没有什么能够阻隔你我
Nothing will keep me from returning to your arms.
日耳曼人不行  罗马人不行
Not the Dacians   not the Romans.
神明也不行
Not the gods themselves.
寒夜寂寥
The nights will be so cold.
无君温存  情何以堪
What will I do without your arms in bed?
掀起裙子
Lift your dress.
让我时刻陪伴你
Keep me close to your thighs.
用它慰藉彼此的牵挂
The thought warm us both.
杀光他们
Kill them all.
就当为了你
For you.
保持阵型
Hold the line!
我要干你们的老婆
I'll fuck your women!
我要干个遍
I'll fuck them all!
罗马军死到哪里去了
Where the hell are the Romans?
手下别留情
Show them no mercy!
罗马军  冲
Romans   fight!
他们去哪了
Where are they going?
来晚了吧
A little late.
他们真碍事
They are just getting in the way.
我拉的屎都比这个好吃
My own shit would taste better.
罗马人给我什么原料我就做什么  卓纳斯
I cook what we give us   Dranus.
这太不公平了  罗马人吃香的喝辣的
This is disgusting. While the Romans feasting on meat
然后让我们饿着肚子
We are the last to eat.
只给残羹剩饭
The last to share the spoils.
但是打仗的时候又让我们冲在最前线
But always the first to be sent against those barbarian cunts.
让混帐葛雷博从温暖的营帐中滚出来
Maybe Legatus fucking glaber could rolls out of his nice warm tent
带着他的人冲锋陷阵
and find their dogs returned from chaos!
有话要说吗  小样儿的
Got something to add   little man?
一句话  哪句话
One word. And which word would that be?
我已经承诺过罗马人
The one that I gave to the Romans.
要全心全意与他们并肩作战
And my body and blood with it.
我们都承诺过了  要击退日耳曼人
We all did to push the Dacians back.
我们不过是想保卫家乡  但做出了承诺
We did it to defend our own land.  We gave our word.
在我的村落里  信奉一诺千金
In my village   such thing still bears meaning.
你的村落
Your village?
你来参战  就是为了保卫"你"的家乡吗
Is that why you're here? To defend your village?
是为了让你那位小情人  觉得你很有
Or maybe you're trying to impress that sweet tits that going about
男子汉气概吧
with stories of war.
我说的一针见血了吧
Striked up your knees   did I?
还说什么承诺与荣耀  真是狗屁
Words and honor my great fat ass.
还不是为了一对玉峰  一处花丛么
All comes the background with a pair of tits and a tight little...
将军来了
The Legatus here.
将军需要志愿者
The Legatus needs volunteers
汇报前线的战况
to sculp beyond the forte line.
你们俩
You!
黎明前给出战术报告
Tactical report by sun rise.
要不然没饭吃
Or go without russians.
他说句"请"能死啊
A "please" would've died.
我们的问题日后解决
We will finish this discussion later.
要是我们死了呢
And if we dead?
那来世我还会追着你痛扁的
Then my boot will find your ass in the next life.
伊莉西娅  就不怕是刺客吗
Ilithyia.  What if I being an assassain?
那我就成寡妇了
I'd be a widow.
我该追悼自己的丈夫多久后才再婚呢
What is the respectful period of mourning before I could remarry?
你越界了
You overstep.
女人是不可以来军营里的
Women are forbidden within camps.
我行踪隐秘呢  是吗
I was discreet. You?
你的人放我过了岗哨
Your man helped me through the sentinels.
因为我威胁说  如果不放我过去
After I threatened to run naked through the camp
我就在军营中裸奔  大喊自己是将军的老婆
screaming in lady's hand of the wife of Legatus.
你爸知道你在特雷斯吗
Does your father know you are in Thrace?
得了吧  他忙着跟元老院里
Please. He is too busy colluding
其他老朽们串通一气呢
with the other corpses in the Senate.
他还以为我在去卡普亚的路上
Think I'm launder in the veadar of Capua.
真没劲啊  人老了  果然是要变糊涂了
Far too irate. The essence of the brain does not last forever?
你该写下来的  你该告诉我不要来
You should've written.  You would've told me not to come.
我在打仗呢  我给你带礼物了
I am in the middle of a war.  I brought you a gift.
能让你想起罗马的礼物
Something to remind you of Rome.
一壶好酒
A flask of wine.
让我给你斟酒
Let me fill up your cup
你来给我讲讲战况吧
while you tell me about your little war.
实在没什么可说的
Too brief to tell.
米特拉达梯人和希腊军向东进发
Mithridates and his Greek army press the legions of the east
侵占黑海
near the Black Sea.
我在这里驻营  保卫北方边境
And here I set   protecting the northern border
迎战那些混帐野蛮人的突袭
of the land of piece of shit from barbarians raiders.
米特拉达梯人
Mithridates?
如果打赢他们  你必定被举国歌颂
A win against have your name on every roman's tongue.
考特领军进攻他们  他这是抢功
Cotta leached the assault.  He steals your laura.
他是执政官  就算抢功我也没话说
He is consul. Thief is his privilege.
父亲会失望的
My father will be disappointed.
他留着位置等你领功呢
He secured this position for you to shine.
但是你在这里驻营的话...  我尽力了
Until you sit   at Clipse.  I am doing what I can.
当然了
Of course you are.
我还是希望你能回家乡
I just wish you were back home.
父亲在筹备盛大的
My father is planning a full day
展览与角斗
with spectacles and gladiators.
整个卡普亚都在谈论呢
It's the talk of Capua.
我都忘了  大选快来了
I havn't realize that the elections were nearing.
竞选永远不嫌早嘛
Never too early to campaign.
如果进展顺利  你可能会成为他的心腹
If things were heading better   you could be by his side.
如果...
If...
这么严肃干嘛  有点幽默感嘛
So serious. Bad for the humors.
来吧
Come.
你还没品尝你的礼物呢
You havn't tasted your gift yet.
他们在解散营地了
They are breaking the camp.
吓破胆的日耳曼人  夹着尾巴溜了
Frightening little Dacians   getting away with their tails between their legs.
他们本应该是向北方山岭撤退的
The retreat will take them to the mountains in the north.
但是火把却指向西方
Their torches bears the west.
西方
West?
他们在周旋  然后攻击沿路的村落
They're swinging around to attack the villages below the path.
我们的村落
Our villages.
狡猾的小兔崽子们
Slippery little cunts!
他们抄山路  最多也就四天
They are breaking the mountain path here. They will take 4 days
就能到达下方的村落
at most to reach the villages below.
食物  补给  妇女
Food   supplies and women.
都得不到保护
All unprotected.
深夜里  群山之中  难免看走眼
It's a simple thing to be turned in the mountains at night.
我应该再派罗马士兵去评估下战势
Perhaps I should send the Romans to properly assess the situation.
你就算派神明来  也还是一样
Send the gods themselves. They will report the same.
退下
Dismissed.
如果我们中午进军  轻而易举的...
If we marched by midday   we can easily...
退下
Dismissed!
野蛮人们西行了
The barbarians head the west.
看起来是的
So it appears.
离米特拉达梯人和希腊人更远了
Further yet from Mithridates and the Greeks.
你离应得的荣耀也更远了
And the glory you deserves.
你回去卡普亚吧
Return to Capua.
怎么跟我父亲交代呢
And my father?
他会怎么看待  自己宝贝女儿的男人呢
How will he measure the man that so blessed with his daughter?
给他建个铜像
As a colossus.
威慑罗马的敌人
Towering above the enemies of Rome.
高傲自大又娘娘腔的罗马人
Pumped arrogant Roman boy lover.
简直是鬼扯  为什么这么说
All the called liars. How would you say?
你听见他怎么说的吧
Heard what he said?
深夜里看走了眼  以为我们是小孩子啊
Turned in the mountains at night   like he's speaking to children.
我是问  你说娘娘腔  那他们站着撒尿吗
No   about the boys   how do you know he pees standing up?
你在说笑吗  我喉咙痒痒
Now who's having a laugh?  There's a tickle at the back of my throat.
你被葛雷博深喉了吧  得了吧
There would be the cock Glaber just forced down. He wants to send
就算他要自己人观察战势  结论也一样
his own man let him. Won't change the direction of Dacians.
葛雷博是最危险的傻瓜
Glaber is the most dangerous kind of fool.
只不过有名头罢了  那是  不过
One with a title. Sure. But perhaps he
他对酒倒是很有品
has better sense when it comes to wine.
你居然偷了他的酒  借来喝两口呗
You stole his wine?  Only borrowed it.
然后过一会再"还"给他
Planned to piss it all back shortly.
起床了  去你妈的
Wake up!  Fuck your mother.
罗马人吹响号角了
The Roman sounded the horn.
去他妈的罗马人  管他们吹不吹的
Fuck the Romans in their horses.
起来
Stand up.
将军应该是醒悟过来了
The Legatus regained his senses.
还有酒吗
Is there any wine left?
你肚子里不是有吗  我马上就排出来了
Your belly holds some.  I will return them presently.
走山路要走多久
How far is the mountain path?
步行三天  如果行军有意义的话
Three days by foot. If we march with meaning.
给我点酒  激发下斗志吧
A drink would spur my intent.
我的村落就在西边不远处
My village is only awast from west.
到了以后管够你喝...  西边?
My wine is yours after...  West?
我们是往东边走  去攻打米特拉达梯人
We march east to challenge Mithridates.
将军后来派人去调查战势了吗
Did Legatus send his own man to discover the front?
我怎么知道
How the fuck should I know?
他们就知道吹号  放狗乱叫
They loaded their horns and Roman dog barks
守卫兵还找我的茬
and the guards shit on me.
欢迎来到魔鬼军队
Welcome to the fucking assari.
跟你谈谈  将军
A word   Legatus.
列队
Move to formation.
我们要东行
We advance east.
你是说西行吧  跟日耳曼人去一个方向
Surely you mean west   as the Dacians advance.
攻打米特拉达梯人和希腊人才是当务之急
Mithridates and the Greeks are our pressing concern.
你们既然投靠了罗马
You have allied yourselves with Rome.
我就是罗马的权代人
I'm its body and voice.
我们东行  去黑海
We march east   to the Black Sea.
列队
Fort formation.
Fort formation!
不
No.
你居然公然反抗你的将军
You will defy order from your Legatus?
我承诺过要全力攻退日耳曼人
I gave my word to defend against the Dacians.
没说过要东行  攻打米特拉达梯人
Not to march east   to attack Mithridates.
我命令你去哪  你就要往哪行军
You will march where you are commanded!
杀光他们
Kill them!
等等
Wait! Wait!
侍卫官跑了
The Tribune!
你他妈的  看看你干的好事
What you've done you stupid shit?
他必须这样做
He did what he had to.
大家散伙各奔东西吧
Break and go your way.
你的村落在西边  就往那走  要不是的话...
To the west if your life is there... If not
我也管不着
I don't give a fuck.
将军怎么处理
What about Legatus?
让他自生自灭
Leave him in the mud.
我们的村落
The village.
我们必须离开这里
We have to go.
马上走
Now!
他们没有追过来
They haven't followed.
你说的对
You were right.
我就不该去
I never should have left.
你跟他保证过的
You had given him your word.
不像他们  随意食言
You're not like the Romans breaking theirs.
你受伤了  没什么
You're hurt.  Nothing.
让我看看  苏拉
Let me see.  Sura.
让我看看
Let me see!
你总吼我  你该习惯了
You tell me just quietly. you should be used by now.
我没事
I'm alright.
还说没事  别动
Of course you are. Stand still.
都没了  是吧
It's gone   isn't it?
我们的村落
The village...
我们的朋友
Everyone we knew.
我们往南走
We move south.
那边有我认识的人
I had people there once.
日耳曼人不会跟那么远
The Dacians won't venture that far.
他们想要保证兵力
They will not take risks in their numbers.
那罗马人呢
And the Romans?
他们关心的是东边的米特拉达梯人
They are concerned about mithridates to the east.
那就往南去吧
South it is.
真希望我自己能以一当百
I wish I have been a thousand men.
你尽力了
You did what you could.
为了我  你回来了
You came back for me.
即便知道会赔上你自己的性命
Knowing you could mean your life.
没有你  我活着又有什么意义
There is no life without you.
我的侍卫官死了
My tribune is dead.
你的将士全当了逃兵
After your auxiliary deserted
我要募集更多的人手
Orders are recalling me to round more of your hands.
一人做事一人当
I own my actions.
我妻子她  沦为奴隶
But my wife...  has been condemned to slavery.
拜其丈夫所赐
Courtesy of her husband.
不  不  不
No. No. No!
在罗马的天罗地网下
Shadow of Rome is fast.
你这个特雷斯人  只不过是瓮中之鳖
And you   Thracian   will die under it.
欢迎加入我们的行列
Good for you to join us.
我差点以为你就这么死了
I thought you were dead there for a while.
已经散发着尸体的臭气了
You smell like dead. Idiot fuck.
淡定  淡定
Easy. Easy!
你都昏迷好几天了
You've been out for days.
我们在海上吗
We are at sea?
亚得里亚海
Upon Adriatic.
往卡普亚方向
Direct to Capua.
我的苏拉  你的女人?
Sura. Your woman?
罗马人带走了她
The Romans took her.
还是忘了她吧
Best forget it then.
不怕我是刺客
And if I being an assassin?
父亲到镇上了  很快就会回来
Father is in town   he will be back shortly.
有多快
How shortly?
父亲对你颇有微词
He is not very happy with you.
那他的女儿呢  很想念你
And his daughter?  She misses her husband.
不过你这么早回来  也让我忐忑
But fears his reappearance has come too soon.
你父亲举办的竞技
The games that your father present to the people of Capua...
明天开始
They begin tomorrow.
今晚是大宴宾客  这是他回来的目的
The feast is tonight?  That is his purpose in town.
我会和他谈谈
I'll have a word with him.
要重获父亲的赏识绝非易事
It will take more than one to regain his favor.
元老院里很多流言  质疑你的
The Senate chamber is full of whispers of your...
提前归来
Early return.
民众的欢呼声自然能堵上他们的嘴
The cheers of the crowd will steal their tongues.
欢呼声  没有胜利哪来的欢呼声
Cheers? How will you draw them short of a victory?
让他们大开眼界就行
By giving something fewer of them have ever seen.
特雷斯人血溅竞技场
Thracian blood spilled the arena.
必定赢得观众的欢心
Winning the hearts of the crowd.
元老院定会拥护你
And the Senate will beg to follow.
滚开
Get out of my sight!
忘恩负义的混蛋们
Ingrate shitholes.
我该把你们都卖到矿区去
I should sell to all of you to the mines.
父亲回来了
Father returned.
心情不错
And in a fine state.
如果你不愿替我美言
If you refuse to add my attention...
只要我装点可怜  父亲会答应我任何事
He will refuse his daughter nothing when pleaded with a teary eye.
亲爱的卡普亚子民们
Dear citizens of Capua.
各位来宾
Guests of honor.
非常感谢大家前来
I have great gratitude for participating
参加阿比努斯家族的庆典
the celebration of family named Albinius.
阿比努斯  阿比努斯
Albinius! Albinius!
各位的光临表达了对先祖的敬意
Your attendance honors the memory of my elders
先祖仙逝多年
who gone too soon for the realm of the living.
幸好膝下仍有一女  带来生命的乐趣
And to the joy of a daughter yet so full of life.
我仅以生命之水作为回报
I repay your kindness with a gift of water.
由罗马带来  携神明之护佑  保天下之富足
Carried from Rome   where the gods saved to keep drought to the bay.
同时我们的竞技场将再掀血雨腥风
And gifts of blood to respill in the arena.
首先有请昆图斯•巴蒂塔斯•兰图拉斯
Quintus Batiatus Lentulus   step forward.
请介绍你的角斗士
Present your gladiators.
尊敬的阿比努斯元老及卡普亚人民
In honor of Senator Albinius and people of Capua...
巴尔卡  我们来自迦太基的猛兽
I give Barca   The Beast of Carthage.
但是  面对克雷斯
However   its savagery pales against the titans of the arena
我们的竞技之王  角斗之神
the god of blood and sand   Crixus.
还是略逊一筹
The undefeated gold.
感谢巴蒂塔斯
Gratitude to Batiatus.
接下来有请
And now...
马尔库斯•德西乌斯•索罗尼斯
Marcus Decius Solonius and its offerings.
尊敬的阿比努斯元老及卡普亚人民
In honor of Senator Albinius and people of Capua...
我带来了六个顶级高手
I bring you 6 of my finest men.
有请  阿凯迪亚斯
Behold   Arkadios
令雅典人闻风丧胆之辈
the scourge of Athens.
狗娘养的
Bastard piece of shit.
造势的行家
A Mockery profession.
怎么造势了  我说的不对么
What mockery is it?  You disagree?
随他去吧
Let him pass.
我们是客人
We're guests of the senator.
元老都邀请我们坐主看台了
He has invited us to sit in the platform tomorrow.
这还有点像话
Little consolation.
我只派了两个人上场
Only two of my men will retain to fight tomorrow
可这家伙派了足足六个人
while Solonius secures half a dozen.
真是个阿谀奉承拍马屁的老手
This man has fingers in all the proper assholes.
还会兴风作浪
He moves and all shit going.
感谢索罗尼斯
Gratitude to Solonius.
但是雨水甘露竞技是属于大家的
But the water and the games didn't just praise
阿尔比努尔斯不敢一人独享
for the city without a name Albinius has its own.
有更多人值得这样的荣耀
More deserves.
神明也赐予我的女儿一个合格丈夫
The gods consider it suitable husband for my daughter.
克罗迪斯•葛雷博将军
Legadus Claudius Glaber.
新近从荒蛮之地特雷斯归来
Newly return from the savage lands of Thrace.
为卡普亚人民
More gifts.
呈上我的心意
For the people of Capua.
六个特雷斯的叛乱之徒
6 Thracians scoundrels.
对日耳曼战争中的无耻逃兵
Deserters from the war against the Dacians barbarians.
明日竞技场上将得到他们应有的审判
To be executed at the gladium in tomorrow's games.
他的呼声挺高的
He is well received.
再有下次  你的眼泪就不值钱了
Ask a favor for him again and your tears will not be short of notice.
美酒仙乐  大家尽情享乐吧
Right   now more music and drink.
特雷斯人
Thracians...
和这群野兽之流搅和
between those animals and Solonius offerings
根本就是笑柄  葛雷博提到审判
That's mockery all it can take.  Glaber mentioned execution
正好我们的人能派上用场
that's what could let our men to do the task.
你们晚了一步
The position has been occupied.
正好  索罗尼斯
Good   Solonius.
我们正说您今晚好一身华服
I was just marveling at your wears.
你也一样
And I yours.
过奖  这是事实
You flatter.  No   I appreciate.
真高兴再见到你  我的老朋友
Good to lay the eyes   old friend.
我还担心或许没邀请你呢
I feared for a time you would be excluded.
若无巴蒂塔斯  再精彩的角斗也黯然失色
Games without Batiatus are like a dorm without a sun.
克雷斯和巴尔卡  不错的选手
Crixus and Barca   2 fine entries.
应该能给我们提供点娱乐消遣
They should provide distraction between the more important battles.
元老叫我了
Senator backens
万一明天没见到你...
If I miss you at the games tomorrow...
不太可能  我们受邀上主看台了
Unlikely   we have been invited to stay in the cabin.
和元老一起观战  莫大的荣耀啊
Cabin with the senator   a great honor.
到时候主看台见了
I'll enjoy your company there.
总有一天我要挖出他的心
I should witness his heart on a day apart from his chest.
那我必定是持刀的那个人
And I should grab the knife.
我还从没见过这种景观
I had never beheld such sights.
以后再也看不见了
And will not consider again.
大家很喜欢这个环节
The crowd approves his gifts.
彼此彼此
That's do we all.
精彩的还在后头
I would hold something of note for the last.
准备受死吧  特雷斯杂种
Ready   Thracian cunt.
看样引起公愤了
You seem out of favor.
这个特雷斯人给罗马造成了极大的危害
This Thracian caused Rome a great disservice  father.
他的怯懦胆小导致了将士们的集体叛逃
He's cowardice led to mass desertion.
那为什么不直接杀了他
His life no longer pays?
我们必须杀鸡儆猴
He must be humiliated   as an example.
索罗尼斯慷慨的提供了手下的角斗士
Solonius was kind enough to offer his services in this act.
下令吧
Give the command.
落人笑柄  淡定
A mockery.  Be still.
杀光他们
Kill them all.
干掉他
Kill!
活命
Live!
这有点棘手了
This present some difficulties here.
死刑的判决不能更改
The sentence of death holds.
违背民意不是明智之举  就算我是元老
But to defy the wished of the crowd is not wise   even for a senator.
他罪大恶极  罪不可赦
He gave me grief   I would not see him free.
将军  我有个办法  不知是否可行
A solution   perhaps   if you're entertained   Legadus.
这特雷斯人在竞技场上表现出过人技艺
The Thracian shows promise in the arena
索罗尼斯的角斗士也不是对手
even if it was men against lower Solonius.
我有一批新人手明天会到
I have a batch of new recruits arriving tomorrow.
可以把这位也归入队伍
If I can departure this man in addition
新人们会在角斗馆内集训
To be trained in my ludis or gladiatorial lots
他目前这状况  估计没多少日子了
By this condition i doubt he could survive to the quarter moon.
还是从宽处理为好
We will be merciful.
你们不也希望赢得百姓的拥戴吗
And by such gain the favor you seek.
他叫什么名字
What name is this man?
无心过问
I never cared to ask.
他角斗的方式
The way he fights
正如关于古特雷斯王的传说
as the legend of the Thracian king of old.
他叫斯巴达克斯
Spartacus he was called.
卡普亚的子民们
People of Capua
这位勇士  斯巴达克斯
this man   this Spartacus
在竞技场上证明了自己
has proven himself in the arena.
为此我和葛雷博将军共同决定
For this   Legadus Claudius Glaber and I grant him...
饶他一死
life.